Guide to the David Barrows Papers, 1836-1870 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
David Barrows papers 1836-1870 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Barrows, David, b. 1830.
0.5 linear feet Extent: 265 Items
Hosiery manufacturer and English emigrant. The collection includes letters, diaries and miscellaneous papers documenting the business enterprises and family life of Barrows.
RL.00098
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The David Barrows Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1984.
Biographical Note
David Barrows was an English emigrant who worked as a hosiery manufacturer.
Collection Overview
Letters, diaries, and miscellaneous papers documenting the business enterprises and family life of a young Englishman who immigrated to Pennsylvania in 1842. Ten diaries (1850-1853) present a detailed account of hosiery manufacture as a family enterprise in which both men and women participated. Community events in Nicetown, Pa., were described as well. Diaries also document the relationship between Barrow and his alcoholic father who was sometimes physically abusive to family members. The author described his efforts to attain financial independence and to create a new life for himself and his wife. Letters from Ann Rusby, a teacher, and diary entries by Barrows, reveal much about their courtship, their sexual relationship and their secret marriage. Letters to and from family members in England depict the contrast in living and working conditions between the two countries. The collection includes an assortment of envelopes arranged by method of sealing.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Alcoholism -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Courtship -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Family violence -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Hosiery industry -- History -- 19th century; Family-owned business enterprises -- United States -- History; Marriage -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Sex customs -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Women -- Sexual behavior -- History -- 19th century; Diaries; Seals
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Information folder (Box 1)
  - Diaries, 1850 Dec. 26-1852 Oct. 16
  - Diaries, 1852 Oct. 17-1853 Apr. 20
  - Correspondence, 1851-1852 June
  - Correspondence, 1852 July-1853
  - Correspondence, 1842-1850
  - Miscellaneous, 1836-1870, undated
  - Envelopes, 1851-1853
  - Envelopes, 1852-1853 (2 folders)
  - Envelopes, 1851-1854